Guide to the Spy Hop Productions independent film collection 2000-2009
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 35)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Interview with a woman, Beverly Dodd, who voted against the Olympics coming to Utah as she was concerned about the impact it would have on the canyons and also worried that the LDS church would use the games as a means to proselyte but Dodd says she feels she was wrong on both counts and is now enjoying the games
    Country band performs on the Medals Plaza stage as people dance in the crowd (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Two young girls, Channel Patterson from Utah and Brianna Brown from Illinois, talk about what they like about the Olympic Games
    Interview with a teen girl, Ida Rodriguez, from Salt Lake City about what the Olympics are about and her involvement in Spy Hop
    Interview with a young woman in a blue and yellow sweater (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a young man in a navy hooded sweatshirt (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a young man in a black parka (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a young man in a white turtleneck (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a young woman in traditional Indian dress (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with another young woman in traditional Indian dress (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a young man in a black parka vest (sound corrupted, no sound)
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 36)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Interview with a young man, Forrest Bennett, who is visiting the Olympics
    Interview with a young girl, Nina Bennett, who is visiting the Olympics
    Interview with, Kelsey Smith, who has been working for the Olympics at one of the venue
    Interview with a local young man, Samsoni Kenu, who feels the Olympics are a waste of time
    Interview with a young man, John Tound, who is a refugee from Sudan and is now living in Utah. Tound discusses his opinions about the Olympics from a foreigner's perspective after living in Utah for six years
    Interview with a young man, John F. Kafu, about his views on the Polynesian cultural events at the Olympics
    Interview with a young woman, Uikelotu Livalosa, about her views on the Olympics in Salt Lake
    Interview with Brad Olsen with CCC Publishing of San Francisco, who had a press pass and was doing new coverage of the Olympics
    Interview with Leslie Tavo, a local teen from Westvale who states she doesn't really care about the Olympics in general because it has no affect on her but who decided to go to the venues and volunteer anyhow
    Interview with Tiare Escui (spelling?) from the Rose Park area of Salt Lake. Escui discusses what the Olympics are about to her, that they haven't really affected her but that she is glad they have come to Utah as the games brought funding to expand and rebuild the roads and freeways
    Interview with Audris Lynn Fayeallen, a local teen at Hillcrest Junior High who enjoys the games but doesn't like the crowds and traffic associated with them
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 37)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Green Screen
    Spray painted wall
    A young boy reads a story he wrote about an animal named Starling to a crowd
    A young girl reads a report she wrote on holidays such as Civil Rights Day and Valentines
    Man in a volunteer blue parka hands out pamphlets
    Man in a green coat hands out pamphlets
    Young boy reads a story about Olympiads "CNN Live Reports the Olympics"
    A young girl reads a story she wrote called "The House We Live In"
    Partial interview with two men handing out pamphlets which contain poems and information about the Olympics
    Interview with young boy who wrote "CNN" followed by a complete reading of his story (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    Interview with a woman in a purple jacket (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    People pass the Budweiser World Party venue
    Neon Manhattan Club sign
    "Live Music Tonight" sign in front of Manhattan Club
    Various shots of Splash, a dance club, on 400 South and West Temple
    Neon alcohol signs in the windows of Port o' Call pub
    Large building sign on the side of the Swiss House
    Interview with a mountain man (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Various shots of a lights show outdoors
    Pedestrians walk by store fronts downtown, night
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 38)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Drummer band performs for a group of people walking around park city
    People wearing parkas with "China" on the back
    Interview with a man, Guoping Zhu, wearing "China" parka, who is in Salt Lake for the first time working as an official for Team China (Interview conducted through an interpreter, Thor Roundy)
    Various shots of beer glasses on a table and a six pack case used as a condiment caddy
    Shot of a group of people wearing "Uncle Sam hats" outside of the Fat Tire Saloon in Park City
    Police officer warms himself by an open fire with two other people
    Black lab sits by the opening to a canvas tent
    People walk down the main strip of Park City
    Exterior shot of Roots in Park City
    Close up on sign which reads "NO berets until Monday afternoon" posted outside of Roots
    Budweiser Clydesdales pull the Budweiser wagon down a road
    People wearing "Uncle Sam hats" walk down road
    Close up, sign "You Can't leave Utah without eating green Jell-o, $1"
    People huddle by an open fire
    Sign on the doorway of a shop which reads "Warm Inside! Welcome to America, enjoy your stay!"
    Shot of two golden labs in goats and on a leash
    Camera crew speaks to police officers who try to shove the interview onto one another
    Interview with both of the police officers (Charles David Seagroves and Frank Luna) about their duties while at the Olympics
    Interview with a man visiting Utah for the Olympics and his family's experience in Park City and Salt Lake
    Quick question with a woman in a Roots beret
    Interview with two young women with Action Ministries, Tracy Hanson from Florida & Jessica Greenway from Texas, trading pins with a message about Jesus Christ
    Shot of a sign which reads "I (heart) NY" on a building
    A woman walking a white miniature goat with a US and an Olympic flag sticking out of its collar
    People warm themselves by a fire in front of a giant USA Hockey jersey
    A young boy and girl compete on virtual snowboards as a commentator gives information about their performances and camera crews film them
    Batmobile on display
    Men assemble a makeshift ski jump sponsored by Budweiser
    A young man performs twists and flips on a trampoline as a crowd watches
    Zoom in on a man walking by ski lift
    Team US merchandise booth
    A young man in a red hooded sweatshirt, Olympic snowboarder (J.J. Thomas?), jumps on trampoline as a crowd watches
    Correspondent for The Tonight Show with Jay Leno, Doug E. Doug (?) talks to young man in red hooded sweatshirt, J.J. Thomas (?), that performed on the trampoline
    People on skis ski down the Budweiser ski jump and land on a snow-covered trampoline as a crowd applauds
    Correspondent for The Tonight Show with Jay Leno, Doug E. Doug (?) talks to young man in red hooded sweatshirt that performed on the trampoline
    Police officers on horseback talk to people in a crowd
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 39)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Interview with a man (first name cut off at beginning of tape, last name Love) who is an Olympic pin collector. Interview includes why he trades pins and what other types of pins he collects (sports).
    Various shots of Olympic pins and memorabilia
    Various shots of downtown shops selling memorabilia
    Shot of the Olympic torch map with up to Idaho lit.
    Power for the People buffalo sculpture (night)
    "Ring, ring, ring, ring, ring" AT&T billboard on a Trax trolley
    Main Street Trax station
    Direction sign for Galivan Center, Capitol Theater, and Shopping district
    Woman performing traditional dance from India on Medals Plaza stage
    Man in a Korea parka with a man in a blue Olympics Parka walk down a busy street
    Pedestrians stand on a sidewalk, others wait at a crosswalk
    Acrobatic dancers perform on Medals Plaza stage; appear to be from an Asian nation
    A cameraman walks around as kids in a band or orchestra warm up
    Women talk in a hall
    Two guys speak in Italian with distorted voices to the camera person filming
    Interview with a young man, Antonio Ardinoinnari, from Sicily who is in Salt Lake who is visiting during the Olympics for vacation. Antonio is asked what the Olympics means to him and what he thought about Salt Lake City before and after he came.
    Kids in a band or orchestra warm up for a rehearsal then begin rehearsal
    Kids in a foyer warm up with their instruments and chat
    Kids in a band or orchestra warm up for a performance in a concert hall (Abravanel Hall)
    A security guard at the concert hall weaves in and out of the isles looking at the floor
    Kids (International and domestic) in a band or orchestra warm up for a performance in a concert hall (Abravanel Hall)
    Interview with Mike Kelley, a member of the Utah Youth Symphony as the kids wait on stage to begin rehearsal
    People wait for performance of the Utah Youth Symphony at Abravanel Hall
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 40)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Interview with a woman in a blue/white striped shirt, Sheri Tayor, about her feelings on the Olympics in Salt Lake and how it's affected her life.
    Shots of a band (Hootie and the Blowfish?) performing on the Medals Plaza stage (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Band playing in a small venue tent. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a young man in a black hooded sweatshirt. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a young woman in denim overalls (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a young woman in a red turtleneck and a white coat. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a young man in a khaki jacket. (sound corrupted, no sound)
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 41)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Exhibit at Abravanel Hall of the glass work of Dale Chihuly
    Shot of Sun sculpture by Dale Chihuly with the LDS Temple Square and Church Office Buildings in background
    Shots of people on the corner of West Temple and South Temple
    Interview with a young man, Danny Thaurer, serving Hot Cocoa to pedestrians along South Temple about his experience with the Olympics thus far.
    Shots of pedestrians along South Temple
    Low shot from a Trax platform
    Interview with a young man, Tocear Uear, from Leon, France who came to Salt Lake City to perform with the Youth Orchestra (plays French Horn) affiliated with the Olympics.
    Youth Orchestra warm up before rehearsal
    Interview with a young man, Haim Mazar, from Telaviv, Israel who came to Salt Lake City to perform with the Youth Orchestra affiliated with the Olympics.
    Shots of a young man playing trombone
    Tocear Uear and another young man perform a duet playing the French National Anthem
    Interview with a young man who plays trombone, Alexandere Mainz from Leon, France who came to Salt Lake City to perform with the Youth Orchestra affiliated with the Olympics.
    Shots of the Utah Youth Orchestra warming up as the conductor is interviewed by a news crew.
    Interview with a young man from Stuttgart, Germany, Arrstle Zimmermann who came to Salt Lake City to perform (French Horn) with the Youth Orchestra affiliated with the Olympics.
    Short performance by Arrstle Zimmerman on the French Horn.
    Various shots of alleyways and garage doors (night)
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 42)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 43)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 44)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Interview with an elderly man in a green shirt who is sitting in a rocking chair (sound corrupted, no sound)
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 45)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Interview with a former Olympic athlete, Igiena Boccalanetro from Caracas Venezuela who competed in the Olympics in Nagano, Japan in 1998.
    Interview with a man in a red baseball cap and a gray hooded sweatshirt. (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a man who is a fan of the Olympics and has attended several of the Summer games, the 2002 Salt Lake City Olympics was his first Winter Olympics.
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 46)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Men's Polynesian dance group performs with clubs on the Medals Plaza Stage (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Polynesian women dance with Poi balls on the Medals Plaza Stage (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Two women perform a Polynesian dance on the Medals Plaza Stage (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Three men perform a Polynesian slap dance on the Medals Plaza Stage (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Two men perform a Polynesian fire dance on the Medals Plaza Stage (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Large group of dancers perform a Polynesian dance on the Medals Plaza Stage (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Young girls perform a Western Shoshone Native American dance on the Medals Plaza Stage
    A young girl, a Western Shoshone Native American from Utah, sings "The Flag Song"
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 47)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Women's Aerials Final (ski jumping)
    Steve Young cheers with a crowd to start "the wave"
    Women's Aerials Final continued
    Winner's presentation
    Women perform a Polynesian dance on a large stage
    A woman hula dances on a large stage as a band plays in the background (out of focus)
    Three young women perform a Polynesian dance as a band plays and sings in the background on a large stage (sound corrupted, no sound)
    A Celtic band performs on the Medals Plaza stage, two little girls dance in the crowd (sound corrupted, no sound)
    People in a crowd on the grounds of the Salt Lake City and County Building watch events on a jumbotron.
    People in a large event tent watch a performance on stage
    Men and women perform a Polynesian dance on the stage of a large event tent
    Men perform a New Zealand native dance for a large group of people in a large event tent
    A large group of children playing violins perform on the Medals Plaza Stage
    A large group of young women and men perform European dances on the Medals Plaza Stage
    People walk around the grounds of the Salt Lake City and County Building (sound corrupted, no sound)
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 48)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Two trainers assist a man on a treadmill
    A young woman explains the Strength Agility program as she walks through the facility at IHC and explains the equipment and their involvement with the Olympic athletes (sound corrupted, sound levels very low)
    Jeff Allred and a young man interviewed (sound corrupted, sound levels very low)
    Interview with a woman in a maroon turtleneck (sound corrupted, sound levels very low)
    People wait on a Trax platform for a shuttle
    A large group of people riding bicycles, accompanied by Olympic security officers on bicycles pass by as people in the background wait on a Trax platform
    Pedestrians walk down a sidewalk in front of the Western States Discovery Center
    Wells Fargo Stage Coach
    Trax train goes west on 500 South by Rice-Eccles Stadium - night
    Olympic torch, night
    People stand in a dark parking light as lights strobe around them
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 49)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Interview with Mark Connors, former US Olympic gymnast, who visited the Utah for the Olympics.
    Interview with a woman in a black suit jacket (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Shots of construction around Temple Square
    Event Traffic Control Ahead sign with Pay Parking sign in back ground
    Liberty Park
    Colonial Flag National Flag Distribution Center office front
    Interview with Dory Peters a Navajo Native American spokesperson for traditional dancers and performers at the Olympics
    Navajo rug hung in an event tent
    People walking around the Navajo rug
    People selling posters at a Navajo event
    Close up of Dory Peters' second book while he talks about it off camera, then zoom out to include him in the frame as they continue to discuss it
    People discuss a display of Navajo rugs
    Dory Peters explains a display for the Navajo culture as he escorts the cameraperson around the exhibit sponsored by the Navajo nation
    Navajo dance performance for a crowd outside of the building holding the Navajo exhibit
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 50)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Street shot, exterior, day.
    Salt Lake Stock Exchange building, exterior
    $10 parking sign
    US and Utah flags waving in the wind
    Wells Fargo building exterior, day.
    US and Utah flags waving in the wind, Christmas lights strung through tree branches in foreground
    American Red Cross First Aid Tent
    Mr. Gabrielison volunteering as a "First Responder" for the American Red Cross First Aid unit and his role in the Olympics.
    Wells Fargo building exterior, night
    Trax trolley
    Flags hanging from the front of a restaurant
    Pedestrians walking down a street, night
    Interview with two young local teens about their views on the Olympics in Salt Lake
    Trax trolley, night
    Mr. Jovan working as a rickshaw driver during the Olympics and his views on the games as a business owner
    Pedestrians watch a parade of a bagpipe and drum band on Main Street downtown, night
    Pedestrians walk down Main Street, night
    People browse and shop at street vender booths
    Focus Sports sign
    Neon lights display
    A rock band performs on a street, Washington Mutual Bank in background, night
    A Peruvian band performs on a street corner (Sound corruption, partial sound)
    Coffee house exterior
    US flag flying slowly in the wind
    Various international flags displayed in a building window
    Shot of the LDS temple, night, techno music playing in the background
    LDS Church Office Building exterior, night
    LDS Salt Lake Temple and reflecting pool, night
    US flag and lit trees, night
    US flag on top of the Walker Oil building, zoom out to pedestrians, night
    Information booth sign
    Pedestrians on street
    A rock band performs on a street corner for a crowd
    A small band of protestors sings about political truce during Olympic Games on a street corner, night (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    People stand on a sidewalk
    A group of drunk young adults yell happily at the camera about Budweiser beer
    A large group of men speaking Spanish speak to the camera
    Police talk to a crowd who was getting out of hand, a small riot erupts and the police arrest some of those involved, night
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 51)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    A street vendor sells US flag hats to a couple of men with young children
    Pedestrians walk down a road from a Trax station near the Delta Center
    Color strobes glare as a band plays in the background
    People dance as a band plays on stage
    Interview with a man working for the "unaccredited media" who doesn't cover the games but other stories related to the games
    Someone holds a sign which reads "Why should god bless America?"
    Sign with reads "Jobs with Justice" plastered in various places
    A street artists paints with a large crowd around him
    Zoom out from LDS Temple Square
    Pedestrians mill around on the corner of
    Interview with George Neckel who is with Utah Jobs with Justice fighting for the rights of worker
    Interview with Amy Heins who is at the Olympics to bring attention to the rights of catering and hotel workers in relation to right to union membership
    Anti-Mormon protesters picket outside of the LDS Temple Square
    Interview with Dale Brown, a Christian from Seattle, picketing outside of the LDS Temple Square
    Exterior Port O' Call pub with a giant inflatable Budweiser Beer bottle on the roof
    Press conference with Salt Lake mayor, Rocky Anderson (sound corrupted, low levels)
    Interview with Mayor Rocky Anderson by ABC
    Cement street partitions painted, near West High School (?)
    Squatters Pub Brewery, exterior
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 52)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Bobsled event
    View of a crowd waiting for the bobsled competition to begin
    Russian team run
    Netherlands team run
    US team run
    Results board
    Team in black and silver (country unknown) stands around after their run
    Team in yellow and blue (country unknown) stands around after their run
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 53)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    A band plays on the Medals Plaza Stage as a crowd listens
    A crowd stands around on the grounds of the Salt Lake City and County Building
    Interview with two young men (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a young man in red and silver face paint (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    Interview with several young men dressed in bodysuits and carrying long boards followed by a competition between a few of them
    A man sings for a small crowd as he dances and plays the guitar
    A street juggler performs for a crowd (sound corrupted, no sound)
    People in USA Hockey Team jerseys cheer in front of the camera (sound corrupted, no sound)
    People dance to techno music in a large event tent